既然没人愿意承认 那就让我来吧
Okay, if no one else will say it, I will.
我们的彩蛋射击技术逊毙了
We really suck at paintball.
简直丢脸丢到家
That was absolutely humiliating.
哦 拜托 胜败乃兵家常事啊
Oh, come on. Some battles you win, some battles you lose.
可也不能输给凯尔那帮犹太小男生啊
Yes, but you don't have to lose to Kyle Bernstein's bar mitzvah party.
我想我们得承认
I think we have to acknowledge,
对方手段太野蛮了
those were some fairly savage preadolescent Jews.
不 我们的惨败是源于我们自己的无能
No,we were annihilated by our own incompetence
以及某些人没有能够听从指挥
and the inability of some people to follow the chain of command.
谢尔顿 别再计较了!
Sheldon,let it go!
不行 我想说说沃罗威茨从背后袭击我的事
No,I want to talk about the fact that Wolowitz shot me in the back.
我有充分的理由
I shot you for good reason.
你正把我们引向灾难之中
You were leading us into disaster.
我的命令清晰而且明确
I was giving clear,concise orders.
你躲在树后面喊 "打那个戴帽子的小孩!
You hid behind a tree yelling,"Get the kid in the yarmulke!
"打那个戴帽子的小孩!"
Get the kid in the yarmulke!"
嗨 你们好
Oh,hey,guys.
- 嗨 佩妮 - 早上好 女士
-Oh,hey,Penny. Hello. -Morning,ma'am.
游戏如何 好玩吗?
So,how was paintball?Did you have fun?
当然 如果你觉得被自己人暗算也开心的话
Sure,if you consider being fragged by your own troops fun.
你最好把日程空出来 我会就此事提出质询的
You clear space on your calendar--there will be an inquiry.
好吧
Okay.
对了 周六我会开个派对
Um,hey,I'm having a party on Saturday,
你们有空的话 不如一起过来玩吧
so if you guys are around,you should come on by.
- 派对? - 是啊
-A party? -Yeah.
是... ‘男女’ 派对?
A... "boy-girl" party?
呃...肯定有男生 也肯定有女生 而且也是场派对
Well,there will be boys and there will be girls and it is a party,so...
其实也就是邀请一帮朋友
It'll just be a bunch of my friends.
喝喝啤酒 跳跳舞
We'll have some beer,do a little dancing.
跳舞?
Dancing?
嗯 我不能确定 佩妮...
Yeah,I don't know,Penny...
其实 我们不太...
The thing is,we're not...
- 我们更适合...  - 不行
-No,we're really more of a... -No.
不过谢谢你能邀请我们
But thanks.Thanks for thinking of us.
确信吗? 来嘛 万圣节哦
Are you sure? Come on,it's Halloween.
万圣节派对?
A Halloween party?
化妆舞会吗?
As in... costumes?
当然了
Well,yeah.
有主题吗?
Is there a theme?
呃 万圣节咯
Um,yeah,Halloween.
是的 不过服装是随自己意呢 还是有风格限制的?
Yes,but are the costumes random,or genre-specific?
和以前一样 我还是没听懂
As usual,I'm not following.
他是想问 我们能不能打扮成科幻片里面的人物 ...
He's asking if we can come as anyone from science fiction,fantasy...
- 当然  - 漫画里的人呢?
-Sure.  -What about comic books?
- 当然   - 动漫?
-Fine.  -Anime?
- 当然了  - 电视 电影
-Of course.  -TV,film,
日本漫画 希腊神话 罗马神话 北欧神话
D- and-D,manga,Greek gods,Roman gods,Norse gods--
什么都行 可以了吗
Anything you want! Okay?
怎么样打扮都行
Any costume you want.
再见
Bye.
各位 向缝纫机前进!
Gentlemen,to the sewing machines.
《生活大爆炸》
第一季  第06集
The.Middle.Earth.Paradigm
我来开
I'll get it.
哦 不
Oh,no.
给世界上速度最快的人让路了!
Make way for the fastest man alive!
哦 不
Oh,no.
看吧 我都说了应该先开会讨论一下嘛
See,this is why I wanted to have a costume meeting.
我们还有别的服装 换一下就可以了
We all have other costumes: We can change.
或者我们可以整晚都保持一列纵队
Or we could walk right behind each other all night
看起来就像是一个人在快速移动
and look like one person going really fast.
不不不
No,no,no.
这是男女派对 闪电侠得单独行动
It's a boy-girl party,this flash runs solo.
不如这样
Okay,how about this?
谁都不许穿成闪电侠
Nobody gets to be The Flash.
全部去换掉 如何?
We all change. Agreed?
同意
Agreed.
我要扮弗拉多!  (电影中人物)
I call Frodo!
该死!
Damn!
嘿
Hey.
抱歉迟到 我的锤子被公交车门卡住了
Sorry I'm late,but my hammer got stuck in the door on the bus.
你要扮雷神托尔?
You went with Thor?
怎么 印度人就不能扮北欧神祗了吗?
What,just because I'm Indian I can't be a Norse god?
"不不 拉杰只能演印度神仙"
"No,no,Raj has to be an Indian god."
这是种族歧视
That's racism.
我说 看看沃罗威茨 他也不是英国人
I mean look at Wolowitz.He's not English,
可是他打扮成了彼得・潘
but he's dressed like Peter Pan.
谢尔顿既不是声波也不是光波
Sheldon is neither sound nor light,
但很明显 他穿成了多普勒效应
but he's obviously the Doppler effect.
我不是彼得潘
I'm not Peter Pan.
我是罗宾汉
I'm Robin Hood.
是啊?
Really?
我看过彼得潘 你穿的和凯西・瑞比一模一样
Because I sawPeter Pan,and you're dressed exactly like Cathy Rigby.
著名百老汇演员 在舞台上饰演该角色24年之久
她比你大了一号 不过造型完全一样 伙计
She was a little bigger than you,but it's basically the same look,man.
谢尔顿
Hey,Sheldon
派对开始前我得先和你谈谈
There's something I want to talk to you about before we go to the party.
我不管别人看不看得懂
I don't care if anybody gets it.
我就是要穿成多普勒效应
I'm going as the Doppler effect.
- 我不是要说这个  - 如果有必要 我会当场演示
-No,it's not that. -If I have to,I can demonstrate.
好极了
Terrific.
这次派对是佩妮第一次
this party is my first chance for Penny
邀请我加入她的社交圈
to see me in the context of her social group,
我希望你今晚不能给我难堪
and I need you not to embarrass me tonight.
你说让你难堪是什么意思?
Well,what exactly do you mean by embarrass you?
比方说 今天晚上
Well,for example,tonight,
没人需要知道我的中间名是里克
no one needs to know that my middle name is Leakey.
这和难堪根本一点关系也没有
But there's nothing embarrassing about that.
你父亲曾经和伟大的人类学家路易斯・里克一起工作过
Your father worked with Louis Leakey, a great anthropologist.
跟你尿床的事一点关系也没有
It had nothing to do with your bed-wetting.
总之我的意思是 这次派对是大好机会
All m saying is that this party is the perfect opportunity for Penny
佩妮可以把我当成她的同伴看待
to see me as a member of her peer group,
一个潜在的亲密好友 或许还能更进一步
a potential close friend,and perhaps more,
我不想看起来像一个怪胎
and I don't want to look like a dork.
先告诉你们 各位
Just a heads up,fellas.
如果有谁交了好运 我的箭筒里有一打套套
If anyone gets lucky,I've got a dozen condoms in my quiver.
嗨 各位
Oh,hey,guys.
嘿 对不起来晚了
Hey. Sorry we're late.
晚?
Late?
才7:05呢
It's 7:05.
你说过派对7点开始
And you said the party starts at 7:00.
没错 可是如果派对定在7点
Well,yeah,I mean,when you start a party at 7:00,
没人会7点就入场
no one shows up at,you know,7:00.
已经7:05了
It's 7:05.
是是 没错
Yes. Yes,it is.
好吧 请进
Okay. Well,um,come on in.
怎么 女生全部去了洗手间吗?
So,what,are all the girls in the bathroom?
很有可能 她们自己家里的洗手间
Probably,but in their own homes.
那个...服装展示什么时候开始?
So,what time does the costume parade start?
展示?
The parade?
对啊 这样评委可以给最佳造型颁奖
Yeah,so the judges can give out the prizes for best costume.
比如最吓人奖 最逼真奖
You know,most frightening,most authentic,
科学原理演示之最佳视觉效果奖
most accurate visualization of a scientific principal.
真抱歉 谢尔顿
Oh,Sheldon,I'm sorry,
可是不会有什么展示
but there aren't going to be any parades
评委或在奖品什么的
or judges or prizes.
这派对一定会很糟糕的
This party is just going to suck.
不！拜托 一定会好玩的
No! Come on,it's going to be fun,
你们看起来都棒极了
and you all look great.
看 你是雷神托尔
I mean,look at you,Thor,
还有~ 彼得・潘 这太可爱了
and,oh,Peter Pan. That's so cute.
- 其实上 佩妮 他是罗宾汉  - 我是彼得・潘
-Actually,Penny,he's Robin Hood. -I'm Peter Pan.
我手里还有一把有你名字的魔法粉
And I got a handful of pixie dust with your name on it.
你才没有
No,you don't.
呃 谢尔顿穿的是什么?
Uh,hey,what's Sheldon supposed to be?
哦 他那是多普勒效应
Oh,he's the Doppler effect.
当声源和观察者之间的距离发生变化时
Yes. It's the apparent change in the frequency of a wave
波动的频率也会发生明显变化
caused by relative motion between the source of the wave and the observer.
哦 我知道了
Oh,sure,I see it now.
多普勒效应嘛
The Doppler effect.
好的 我得去洗澡了
All right,I got to shower.
你们 自己好好玩吧
You guys,um,make yourselves comfortable.
好的
Okay.
瞧见没? 人们能明白的
See? People get it.
以奥丁的胡子起誓 实在太好吃了
By Odin's beard,this is good Chex mix.
奥丁 北欧神话中的主神
不用了 谢谢 有花生
No,thanks. Peanuts.
穿这么紧 我可不能肿起来
I can't afford to swell up in these tights.
我搞不懂
I'm confused.
如果没有服装展示 我们在这干吗?
If there's no costume parade,what are we doing here?
参与社交活动啊 认识新朋友
We're socializing,meeting new people.
靠传心术吗?
Telepathically?
嗨 你们什么时候来的?
Oh,hey,when did you get here?
嗨
Hi.
佩妮的那件猫女装是我见过最丑的
Penny is wearing the worst Catwoman costume I've ever seen.
比哈里・贝瑞还差
And that includes Halle Berry's.
哈里・贝瑞 她曾因一片勇夺金酸梅最差女主角
她不是猫女 只是一只普通的猫
She's not Catwoman. She's just a generic cat.
正是由于竞争机制的缺乏
And that's the kind of sloppy costuming
才会导致这种三流造型的出现
which results from a lack of rules and competion.
嘿 快瞧那个性感小护士
Hey,guys,check out the sexy nurse.
我相信是时候采取行动了
I believe it's time for me to turn my head and cough.
你准备怎么做?
What is your move?
采取镜子战术
I'm going to use the mirror technique.
她拨她的头发 我就拨我的
She brushes her hair back,I brush my hair back...
她耸肩 我也耸肩
She shrugs,I shrug.
她下意识里就会觉得 我们心有灵犀 注定是一对
Subconsciously she's thinking,"We're in sync. We belong together."
你哪学来的这一套?
Where do you get this stuff?
心理学期刊 国际性研究
You know,psychology journals,Internet research,
而且在VH-1台上也有教如何追求女孩的好节目
and there's this great show on VH-1 about how to pick up girls.
我有他那么自信就好了
Oh,if only I had his confidence.
我跟女人说话都困难 呆在女生旁边也是...
I have such difficulty speaking to women,or around women...
甚至包括娘娘腔的男人
or at times even effeminate men.
如果那个听诊器能正常使用
If that's a working stethoscope,
或许你想听听我击鼓般的心跳声?
maybe you'd like to hear my heart skip a beat?
不用了
No,thanks.
我说真的 我有瞬间自发性心律失常
No,seriously,you can.I have transient idiopathic arrhythmia.
我想去认识佩妮的朋友们
I want to get to know Penny's friends,
我只是… 但我不知道该怎么和这些人说话
I just… I don't know how to talk to these people.
这点上 我可能会帮上忙
Well,I actually might be able to help.
怎么说?
How so?
就像珍・古德观察黑猩猩一样
Like Jane Goodall observing the apes,
英国科学家 以对黑猩猩的研究闻名世界
我发现一开始他们之间的互动是混乱且无组织性的
I initially saw their interactions as confusing and unstructured.
但渐渐有模式可循
But patterns emerge.
他们有自己独特的语言
They have their own language,if you will.
继续
Go on.
新来的人在接近现有的一伙聊天的人时 会说
Well,it seems that the newcomer approaches the existing group with the greeting,
"我看起来喝醉了吗?"
"How wasted am I?"
然后就会有一阵类似“伙计”之类的欢迎声
Which is met with an approving chorus of "Dude."
然后呢?
Then what happens?
我只观察到这些
That's as far as I've gotten.
真是荒谬
This is ridiculous.
我准备上了
I'm jumping in.
祝你好运
Good luck.
不 你跟我一起
No,you're coming with me.
我可不这么想
Oh,I hardly think so.
拜托
Oh,come on.
你不怕我给你难堪?
Aren't you afraid I'll embarrass you?
怕 可我需要一个副手
Yes; but I need a wing man.
wingman:原意指护航的飞机
好吧 可是如果要拿飞行来做比喻的话
All right,but if we're going to use flight metaphors,
我更适合联邦航空局事故调查员的角色
I'm much more suited to being the guy from the FAA analyzing wreckage.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨 - 你好
Hi. Hello.
你这身是扮的是什么?
So what are you supposed to be?
我? 我给点提示
Me? I'll give you a hint.
玩具火车?
A choo-choo train?
接近了!
Close!
一列脑震荡的火车?
A brain damaged choo-choo train?
我看起来喝醉了吗?
How wasted am I?
我还是不懂
I still don't get it.
我是多普勒效应
I'm the Doppler effect.
如果这是指一种"学习障碍"
Okay,if that's some sort of learning disability,
那么你也模仿得太烂了
I think it's very insensitive.
为什么不跟别人说你是只斑马呢?
Why don't you just tell people you're a zebra?
那你怎么不告诉人家你是 七个小矮人之一?
Well,why don't you just tell people you're one of the seven dwarves?
因为我是弗拉多
Because I'm Frodo.
没错 很好 因为我是多普勒效应
Yes,well,I'm the Doppler effect.
- 不会吧 - 怎么了?
-Oh,no.  -What?
那是佩妮的前男友
That's Penny's ex-boyfriend.
他来这里干吗?
What do you suppose he's doing here?
干扰这里的重力场吗?
Besides disrupting the local gravity field.
他要是再大块点 月亮都会绕着他转
If he were any bigger,he'd have moons orbiting him.
你真刻薄
Oh,snap.
那么 我们似乎该走了
So,I guess we'll be leaving now.
为什么要我们走?
Why should we leave?
很明显他是不请自来 佩妮看都不想看他
For all we know he crashed the party and Penny doesn't even want him here.
还有后备的假设吗?
You have a backup hypothesis?
也许他们只是想做回朋友
Maybe they want to be friends.
又或者她想做朋友 而他想要更多
Or maybe she wants to be friends and he wants something more.
那么他和我就在同一高度
Then he and I are on equal ground.
没错 但你比他更接近地面
Yes,but you're much closer to it than he is.
如果是1500年前
Look,if this was 1,500 years ago,
凭他的体格和力量
by virtue of his size and strength,
科特想挑选哪个女人都可以
Kurt would be entitled to his choice of female partners.
还有男人 动物 巨型远古茄子
And male partners,animal partners, large primordial eggplants--
几乎所有他想要的东西
pretty much whatever tickled his fancy.
没错 但现在的社会已经发生了根本的转换
Yes,but our society has undergone a paradigm shift.
在信息时代 谢尔顿
In the Information Age,Sheldon,
你和我才是最优秀的
you and I are the alpha males.
我们不该退缩
We shouldn't have to back down.
是的
True.
你干吗不发短信给他看他会不会退缩?
Why don't you text him that and see if he backs down?
不
No.
我要面对面向他展现我的优势
I'm going to assert my dominance face-to-face.
面对面? 你是要他坐下
Face-to-face? Are you going to wait for him to sit down,
还是自己站在咖啡桌上?
or are you going to stand on the coffee table?
嗨 佩妮
Hello,Penny.
嗨 科特
Hello,Kurt.
嗨 你们玩得还好吗?
Oh,hey,guys,are you having a good time?
鉴于人们对我扮相的反应
Given the reaction to my costume,
这次派对是对美国教育制度的严厉控诉
this party is a scathing indictment of the American education system.
你是斑马 对吧?
What,you're a zebra,right?
有一个低能儿童
Yet another child left behind.
你又是什么 精灵?
And what are you supposed to be,an elf?
不 我是霍比特人
No,I'm a hobbit.
有什么不同?
What's the difference?
霍比特人是居住在中土世界 生命有限的矮人
A hobbit is a mortal halfling inhabitant of Middle Earth,
而精灵则是永生而高大的战士
whereas an elf is an immortal,tall warrior.
那你为什么要做个矮人呢?
So why the hell would you want to be a hobbit?
因为他既不高也会死
Because he's neither tall nor immortal
而且我们没有人可以做闪电侠
and none of us could be The Flash.
随你怎说
Well,whatever.
不如你们赶紧消失
Why don't you go hop off on a quest?
我正和佩妮说话呢
I'm talking to Penny here.
我想我们都在和佩妮说话
I think we're all talking to Penny here.
我没有 我没恶意
I'm not. No offense.
好吧 可能你没听懂我意思
Okay,maybe you didn't hear me.
- 滚蛋 - 好啦 科特 有礼貌点
-Go away.  -All right,Kurt,be nice.
我很有礼貌
Oh,I am being nice.
对不对 小朋友?
Right,little buddy?
- 科特 - 好吧
-Kurt.  -Okay.
我明白你企图用武力来恐吓我
I understand your impulse to try to physically intimidate me.
因为你在智力上无法和我匹敌
I mean,you can't compete with me on an intellectual level
所以你只能选择这种动物似的方式
so you're driven to animalistic puffery.
你是说 我是动物吗?
You calling me a puffy animal?
当然不是啦 不 他不是
Of course not. No,he's not.
你不是 对吧 莱纳德?
You're not,right,Leonard?
不 我是说"动物似的"
No,I said "animalistic."
当然我们都是动物
Of course we're all animals,
只不过我们当中一些人 在进化树上爬得更高一些
but some of us have climbed a little higher on the evolutionary tree.
要是他听懂了 你就完蛋了
If he understands that,you're in trouble.
所以怎样 你说我没进化吗?
So,what,I'm unevolved?
你完蛋了
You're in trouble.
作为一个侏儒 你用的词还真够大的
You know,you use a lot of big words for such a little dwarf.
好吧 科特 别这样
Okay,Kurt,please.
佩妮 没关系 我可以处理
Penny,it's okay. I can handle this.
我不是侏儒
I am not a dwarf,
我是霍比特人
I'm a hobbit.
一个霍比特人...
A hobbit.
你大脑海马区里坏掉的神经元
Are misfiring neurons in your hippocampus preventing the conversion
阻碍了短期记忆到长期记忆的转换吗
from short-term to long-term memory?
好吧 现在你惹火我了
Okay,now you're starting to make me mad.
一个发现自己可对立拇指的人猿说什么?
A homo habilis discovering his opposable thumbs says what?
什么?
What?
我想我已经说得很清楚了
I think I've made my point.
是吗? 不如我在你的小脑袋上 凿个洞让你更清楚点?
Yeah? How about I make a point out of your pointy little head?
我要提醒你 尽管精神上我绝对支持你
Let me remind you,while my moral support is absolute,
但在肢体冲突上 我的作用是零
in a physical confrontation,I will be less than useless.
根本就不会有什么冲突的
There's not going to be a confrontation.
说实话 我怀疑他能不能拼 "冲突"这个单词
In fact,I doubt if he can even spell "confrontation."
C-O-N...
frontation!
科特 马上放他下来
Kurt,put him down this instant!
他先惹我的
He started it!
我不管 我想结束这事 总之放下他
I don't care. I'm finishing it.Put him down!
好吧
Fine.
算你个妖精走运
You're one lucky little leprechaun.
他是霍比特人!
He's a hobbit!
我顶你
I got your back.
莱纳德 你没事吧?
Leonard,are you okay?
我很好
Yeah,I'm fine.
这派对很棒 谢谢你邀请我们
It's good,it's a good party,thanks for having us.
时间也不早了 所以...
It's just getting a little late,so...
好吧
Oh,okay.
好吧 谢谢你们能来
All right,well,thank you for coming.
万圣节快乐
Happy Halloween.
如果这也算安慰的话
If it's any consolation,
我想说 你那句"人猿"的确很适合他
I thought that homo habilis line really put him in his place.
那是什么?
What's that?
茶
Tea.
当人们沮丧的时候
When people are upset,
传统上应该给他们一点热饮
the cultural convention is to bring them hot beverages.
好啦 好啦
There,there.
要谈谈吗?
You want to talk about it?
- 不 - 太好了
-No.  -Good.
我能说的也只有"好啦 好啦"了
"There,there" was really all I had.
晚安 谢尔顿
Good night,Sheldon.
晚安 莱纳德
Good night,Leonard.
嘿 莱纳德?
Hey,Leonard?
嗨 佩妮
Hi,Penny.
我只是来看看你有没事
Hey,I just wanted to make sure you were okay.
我很好
I'm fine.
刚才的事真不好意思
I am so sorry about what happened.
那不是你的错
It's not your fault.
不 怪我
Yes,it is.
这就是我和他分手的原因
That's why I broke up with him.
他总是这样
He always does stuff like that.
那他怎么会出现在派对上?
So why was he at your party?
上周我碰见他 他道歉说他已经变了
Well,I ran into him last week and he was just all apologetic about how he's changed.
他不停的说啊说…
And he was just going on and on and...
我就相信了 我真是个笨蛋
I believed him and I'm an idiot
因为我总是那么容易相信那种男人
because I always believe guys like that.
我根本不想回去 因为他还待在那
And I can't go back to my party because he's there.
我知道你不想听这些 但我很伤心
And know you don't want to hear this and I'm upset
还喝醉了 我只想...
and I'm really drunk and I just want to...
好啦 好啦
There,there.
天啊 我做错什么了吗?
God,what is wrong with me?
没有 你很完美
Nothing,you're perfect.
我不完美
I'm not perfect.
不 你是
Yes,you are.
你真的这么想?
You really think so,don't you?
佩妮?
Penny?
恩?
Yeah?
你今晚喝了多少?
How much have you had to drink tonight?
就...很多
Just... a lot.
你确信你不是因为喝醉酒而且对科特的事生气
Are you sure that your being drunk and your being angry with Kurt
现在才这样做吗
doesn't have something to do with what's going on here?
可能有吧
It might.
你太聪明了
Boy,you're really smart.
是啊 我TMD就是个天才
Yeah,I'm a frickin' genius.
莱纳德 你真是太好了
Leonard,you are so great.
为什么男人都不能像你这样？
Why can't all guys be like you?
如果是那样的话
Because if all guys were like me,
人类就无法繁衍了
the human race couldn't survive.
我想我该走了
I should probably go.
是的
Probably.
谢谢
Thank you.
是的 你没看错
That's right,you saw what you saw.
我们在夏尔也是这么狂欢的
That's how we roll in the Shire.
中弗拉多的家乡
来了
Coming.
嘿 看见库萨帕里了吗?
Hey,have you seen Koothrappali?
他不在这
He's not here.
也许复仇者们把他召走了
Maybe the Avengers summoned him.
他不是神奇漫画里那个雷神 是北欧神话里那个雷神
He's not the Marvel Comics Thor,he's the original Norse god.
多谢你的解释
Thank you for the clarification.
我本来要送他回家的
I'm supposed to give him a ride home.
放心吧 我相信他没事的
Well,I'm sure he'll be fine.
他带着锤子呢
He has his hammer.
我得承认 你太了不起了
I have to say,you are an amazing man.
温柔 有激情
You're gentle,and passionate.
而且 上帝啊 你还是个超好的倾听者
And,my God,you are such a good listener.